They're young, desperate, dangerous—a long way from
home, but a short way from Hell.
Bad Company is a western, drama film directed by Robert Benton.
After Drew Dixon, an upright young man, is sent west by his religious family to avoid being drafted into
the Civil War, he drifts across the land with a loose confederation of young vagrants.
Jake Rumsey, played by Jeff Bridges.
Drew Dixon, played by Barry Brown.
Big Joe, played by David Huddleston.
Arthur Simms, played by Jerry Houser.
Hobbs, played by Geoffrey Lewis.
Orin, played by Ed Lauter.
Bad Company is a 1972 American Western film directed by Robert Benton (in his
directorial debut), who also co-wrote the film with David Newman.
It stars Barry Brown and Jeff Bridges as Jake Rumsey and Drew Dixon, two of a group of young men who flee the draft
during the American Civil War to seek their fortune and freedom on the unforgiving American frontier.
Later classified by critics as an acid Western, Bad Company attempts in many ways to demythologize the American West in its portrayal of young
men forced by circumstance and drawn by romanticized accounts to forge new lives for themselves on the wrong side of the law.
Their initial eagerness to be outlaws soon abates, however, when the boys are confronted with
the realities of preying on others in a nation ravaged by war and exploitation.
The film is often credited with inspiring the name of the classic rock band of the seventies Bad Company which according to Paul Rodgers (the
band's lead singer) is incorrect and the name is in fact taken from an illustration in a Victorian book of morals he once perused.
The film explores themes of runaway, marshal, loyalty, missouri, betrayal.
The tone is emotional.